namibian.com.na 2018-12-27

# The Namibian

##  Sport 

* * *

2018-12-26

## [Liverpool open up six-point lead as Man City lose again at Leicester](https://www.namibian.com.na/74340/read/Liverpool-open-up-six-point-lead-as-Man-City-lose-again-at-Leicester "Click to read full article")

LONDON - Liverpool moved six points clear at the top of the Premier League as the leaders eased past Newcastle 4-0 at Anfield and Manchester City were beaten for the second time in five days, 2-1 at Leicester.

* * *

2018-12-26

## [Olivier steals limelight from record breaker Steyn](https://www.namibian.com.na/74339/read/Olivier-steals-limelight-from-record-breaker-Steyn "Click to read full article")

CENTURION - Fast bowler Duanne Olivier was almost apologetic for stealing the limelight from record-breaker Dale Steyn after 15 wickets fell on the first day of the first Test between South Africa and Pakistan at SuperSport Park on Wednesday.

* * *

2018-12-25

## [Resurgent Djokovic leads the way as old guard stays on top](https://www.namibian.com.na/74334/read/Resurgent-Djokovic-leads-the-way-as-old-guard-stays-on-top "Click to read full article")

PARIS - Next Gen poster boy Alexander Zverev's season-ending Tour Finals triumph served up a glimpse into the future of men's tennis although 2018 remained a year dominated once more by the usual, yet ageing, suspects as a revitalised Novak Djokovic returned to the peak of his powers.

* * *

##  Entertainment 

* * *

2018-12-20

## [Heatwave Festival 2018 to rock the coast](https://www.namibian.com.na/74195/read/Heatwave-Festival-2018-to-rock-the-coast "Click to read full article")

RUKEE KAAKUNGA; NETUMBO NEKOMBA

STAGE thriller Sally Boss Madam will be headlining the Heat Festival taking place at The Dome, Swakopmund on Friday, 28 December.

* * *

2018-12-20

## [Exit to launch latest album at NYE bash](https://www.namibian.com.na/74196/read/Exit-to-launch-latest-album-at-NYE-bash "Click to read full article")

POPULAR kwaito artist Exit is launching his latest album at a New Year's bash that's set to take place at Bennie's Entertainment Park at Ongwediva on 31 December

* * *

2018-12-20

## [From The Twittersphere](https://www.namibian.com.na/74197/read/From-The-Twittersphere "Click to read full article")

Aaand it's a wrap, folks! Herewith the last Twittersphere for 2018. Wishing you and yours a fabulous festive season, a cheerful Christmas and a noteworthy New Year. Please be safe out there – don't drink and drive, take it easy and stick to the speed limit. Appreciate the scenery, and each other. Till next year, xo.

* * *

##  Business 

* * *

2018-12-21

## [Cost-cutting painful but necessary – Schlettwein](https://www.namibian.com.na/74287/read/Cost-cutting-painful-but-necessary-%E2%80%93-Schlettwein "Click to read full article")

LAZARUS AMUKESHE

FINANCE minister Calle Schlettwein has admitted that the ministry's cost-cutting measures brought certain negatives on domestic industries that depended on the government.

* * *

2018-12-21

## [NSX stocks and deals](https://www.namibian.com.na/74288/read/NSX-stocks-and-deals "Click to read full article")

LAZARUS AMUKESHE

WORKERS BUY OLD MUTUAL SHARES

INSURANCE company Old Mutual Limited's workers have bought about 103 000 shares in the company at the value of atN$2,2 million.

* * *

2018-12-21

## [Husab aims for 5 000tonnes uranium next year](https://www.namibian.com.na/74289/read/Husab-aims-for-5-000tonnes-uranium-next-year "Click to read full article")

SWAKOP Uranium's Husab mine is set to drum 5 000 tonnes of uranium oxide (U3O8) next year, according to a statement issued by the company's executive committee this week.

* * *

## Poll

* * *

Do you think president Geingob opening Sisa Namandje's building constituted a conflict of interest?

##  Your Privacy 

* * *

The Namibian is fully committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. We have structured our web site so that, in general, you can visit The Namibian on the Web without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information.

Once you choose to provide us personally identifiable information (any information by which you can be identified), you can be assured that it will only be used to support your customer relationship with The Namibian, or to provide you access to areas of the web site to which you wish to have access.

This statement regarding the privacy of the personally identifiable information you provide online covers the five foundation principles of fair information:

## Awareness

The Namibian provides this Online Privacy Statement to make you aware of our privacy policy, practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and from the bottom of every page on www.namibian.com.na.

  *  _What we collect_  
On some pages of www.namibian.com.na you can make requests, and register to receive materials, or become a member of The Namibian's online community. The types of personal information collected at these pages are your name, surname, e-mail address and address details.

In order to tailor our subsequent communications to you and continuously improve our products and services (including registration), we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experience with our products, and more detailed contact preferences. Some electronic newsletters record anonymous data about articles you have expressed interest in.

Some www.namibian.com.na web pages use cookies, a data analysis technique.

  *  _How we use it_  
The Namibian uses your information to better understand your needs and provide you with better service. Specifically, we use your information to help you complete a transaction, to communicate back to you, to update you on service and benefits, and to personalise our web sites for you.

From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research or to provide you with marketing information we think would be of particular interest. At a minimum, we will always give you the opportunity to opt out of receiving such direct marketing or market research contact.

We will also follow anylocal requirements, such as allowing you to opt in before receiving unsolicited contact, where applicable.

  *  _Who we share it with_  
The Namibian will not sell, rent, or lease your personally identifiable information to others. Unless we have your permission or are required by law, we will only share the personal data you provide online with other entities of The Namibian and/or business partners who are acting on our behalf for the uses described in 'how we use it'.

Such entities and/or business partners, including those in the Republic of Namibia and/or any other countries, are governed by our privacy policies with respect to the use of this data and are bound by the appropriate confidentiality agreements.

  *  _Children's Privacy Protection_  
The Namibian also takes special care to protect the privacy needs of children under the age of 13 and encourages parents to be an active participant in their child's online activities and interests.  

* * *

## Choice

The Namibian will not use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without first letting you know and offering you a choice.

As previously stated, we will also provide you the opportunity to let us know if you do not wish to receive unsolicited direct marketing materials from us and we will do everything we can to honor such requests.

Your permission is always secured first, should we ever share your information with third parties that are not acting on our behalf and governed by our privacy policy.

* * *

## Accuracy & Access

The Namibian strives to keep your personally identifiable information accurate. We will provide you with access to your information, including making every effort to provide you with online access to your registration data so that you may view, update or correct your information at the HP site where it was submitted. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access or enabling you to make corrections. To access your personally identifiable information, return to the web page where you originally entered it and follow the instructions on that web page. Certain areas of The Namibian's web site may limit access to specific individuals through the use of passwords and through providing personally data.

Links to third party web sites on the site are provided solely as a convenience to you. If you use these links, you will leave The Namibian's web site.

The Namibian has not reviewed all of these third party sites and does not control and is not responsible for any of these sites, their content or their privacy policy. Thus, The Namibian does not endorse or make any representations about them, or any information, software or other products or materials found there, or any results that may be obtained from using them. If you decide to access any of the third party sites linked to this site, you do so at your own risk.

* * *

## Security

The Namibian is committed to ensuring the security of your information. To prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

* * *

## Oversight

If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy, please email ([info at namibian.com.na]()) us.

* * *

## How The Namibian uses Cookies

A cookie is a piece of text asking permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. If you agree, then your browser adds the text in a small file. The purpose of a cookie is to help us analyse web traffic or let us know when you visit a particular site.

Cookies allow a web application to respond to you as an individual. By gathering and remembering information about your preferences, the web application can tailor its operation to your needs, likes and dislikes. 

For example, when you visit an area in The Namibian's online community, a cookie makes it easy to tell you whether there are any new messages that you have not read/accessed.

The Namibian uses traffic log cookies to identify what pages are being used and which ones aren't. This helps us aggregate and analyse data about web page traffic and make improvements to www.namibian.com.na to better meet customer needs.

In this case, The Namibian uses this information only for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. That is the case of many of our support and information-sharing pages and forums. Denial of a traffic log cookie should not prevent you from using one of these sites.

Overall, cookies help us give you a better web site to use, by letting us monitor what's working and what isn't through site traffic analysis. The Namibian wants to be sure you understand that accepting a cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any personal information about you, other than the data you chose to share with us. This practice is strictly enforced. We know that a lot of people have concerns about cookies, but in talking with many of our customers, we believe that the benefit we both gain from their proper use is worthwhile. We value the relationships we have with our customers, so we respect these concerns. The Namibian works to continuously improve the www.namibian.com.na web experience and personal data privacy policy and practices.

You may set your web browser (MicroSoft Internet Explorer or Netscape Navigator) to notify you of cookie placement requests or decline cookies completely. You can delete the files that contains cookies; those files are stored as part of your internet browser.

* * *
